[Music]
I'm ready. Okay.
This is story of my song by American
Express. So, what we're all looking at
is a screenshot of my notes app from the
day that Audrey and I wrote this song
together.
It's funny to see it written here like
ooh
Can't wait to dissect that one together.
The song itself is really about feeling
mildly petty at the outcome of not
feeling wanted, watching somebody that
you have feelings for go off with the
next person. The last time we touched
these lyrics was May 17th, 20 24. Okay,
let's get into it. First one.
[Music]
Your promise really for this first
section is
feeling like you know someone so well
that no words are required to understand
exactly what it is they're thinking.
[Music]
I think you're dumb but I you're in my
head constantly. Sort of this like push
and pull between like I'm so over it,
it's so embarrassing, you're so
embarrassing, but clearly they're
occupying a lot of the space in your
head.
This is like wanting the person to
understand that you see right through it
all, but also simultaneously
that's a little embarrassing.
Okay, this piece felt important to
Audrey and I and I remember us between
sips of wine kind of listing all of the
potential qualities that we could
dissect about her.
I think as a brown-eyed person sometimes
people with blue eyes are like
why'd you get that? It's a good thing to
have.
[Music]
I also do think that like this song is a
good example of how being like broken up
with can
sort of trigger some pretty like
navel-gazing, a bit self-centered, or
like mildly narcissistic thoughts to
come up. I think I'm a bigger person
than these lyrics would suggest, but
we ultimately ended up writing the
lyrics really, really quick. Every song
I've ever really cared about making,
you're kind of just pulling it out of
thin air a little bit and then there's
like a mini blackout period where you
then like hear it in full at the end and
it just it's like it just appeared.
I'm not one to like put it ah in my
songs necessarily, but this felt
important. The song is riddled with kind
of petty attitude and like just lots of
emphasis on the kind of brattier parts
in this one.
That's embarrassing.
It's embarrassing to think that.
Let's hit the pre.
[Music]
We loved writing this. It's kind of like
being so bold in
your judgment of someone. This song in
particular I think is like a funny one
to kind of dissect because it's all very
direct, which is what we wanted. I think
it was like the idea of being able to
not have to read into any of the lyrics.
It's not like a revenge song or anything
like that. It's just like a real
expression of feeling wronged and being
petty about it. It's not too decorated.
So, you're an idiot.
Now I'm sure, now I'm positive. It's
like okay.
I always find when we're writing songs I
get as much rhythm and almost like use
the guitar as like a percussive element.
You know, if you're on the road and you
don't have access to a studio with a
drum kit or like a drum machine to be
able to try to like have as much of the
feel in the guitar itself. So, that was
the
uh
with the like the um
hammering even.
We just
I don't know. We just wanted to feel
good. We wanted it to feel good. Let's
go into the chorus.
[Music]
Chorus.
My favorite. We were in the studio
cutting this pretending to be owls.
Aaron would be like you guys got to you
got to get it together cuz we have a
vocal to cut we'd be like
This was kind of the bit that was stuck
in our heads for months before we
actually came around to finishing the
song. I think the whole theme really was
like about getting to this piece where
you're like I do know everything because
I have been in her shoes. I've been
there. I've done that. I know exactly
what's going down and again further kind
of like mockery
of the person that has let you down by
literally just simply not choosing you.
You know, normal thing to feel. Okay,
verse two we've got a portion of it.
I love this part.
[Music]
Okay.
I love this verse so much. Similarly to
the blue eyes piece, I had recently cut
my hair off. So, I felt like that's
another thing that we could point to
that I
I was like well maybe it's cuz she's got
gorgeous long hair you know what I mean.
All this stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid,
stupid stuff.
I would say
the aggression and the satisfaction in
the voices of the audience
here or twice. It's real punchy from the
audience. So, I appreciate that very
much. Audrey and I played this song for
the first time at one of our shows at
the Greek in LA. This line did that once
or twice she goes or twice ah and now in
the crowd every everywhere we go they're
like boom. So, you know, I feel like I
get to hang out with my friend in some
like funny way every every show even
though she's not there. Okay, we have to
finish the verse.
I'm just kidding.
[Music]
So, you're kind of like I did that once
or twice and then it's kind of like
okay, I know I'm being ridiculous, but
can't be stopped. The thoughts just keep
coming. Just
But I do think like there's actual
sincerity in this feeling where you can
really start to admire that person even
if you don't know them at all from all
the little clues and bits that you can
gather being like oh she's probably the
coolest, smartest
hottest, etc. And then it flips just 2
seconds later. The music I grew up
listening to there are callbacks just
references to previous sections in a
song, but you're kind of pushing the
story forward a bit by just tweaking it.
First pre had go and warn her.
[Music]
And then it flips you want to warn him
that she just doesn't understand.
You're just changing it enough to keep
the narrative moving forward. I feel
scared to talk about the
uh bridge.
We'll get there. You know, you we can
dissect this, but like I would never say
the names of the people that the song's
about for example, but I think you know,
I actually I don't have any problem
standing here being like yes, I wrote
this about a relationship that I was
involved in, but anyone that I've ever
been involved with for example like
knows that I write songs. There's just a
way to
make someone aware
when you've done it if it's going to see
the light of day for example, enough
consideration,
you know, to be respectful of X, Y, Z
person in their personal life and
experiences. Yeah, the person's fine.
They're all good. Double chorus.
That's cute.
[Music]
Love it. Structurally we knew in our
heads this would be a double hook, but
this point felt crucial and then
obviously here we go. There's our title,
which made us laugh.
Just being like that's so true. It's
kind of the voice in your head talking
to yourself, you know, he's just another
dude. People say we say that all the
time. Like we say that's so true all the
time in our
normal non-songwriting conversations.
So, that's our hook.
There we are. I feel like we should
probably move into the bridge. Let's do
first chunk of this bridge and then
there's more on the other side of the
sheet, I have to assume.
Okay.
I'm being too
precious with the paper. Ready? That's
my life.
Price. Okay, I'm just going to kick over
this so I
contradicting myself left and right.
Made it out alive, but I think I lost it
so that I was fine, said it from my
coffin. We're getting really serious.
Oh, I should probably get back on the
stage. The whole thing is sort of being
like, "Don't you understand how painful
this has been?" I don't totally
understand what I was doing here.
Another sound to incorporate, it seems.
Just to be clear, in reality, there's no
taking out my earrings to fight. Like,
nothing about the desperation that you
hear in this person's voice was even
remotely based in reality.
My favorite thing about a song tends to
be a bridge. You know, Taylor is an
amazing example of this. Like, you're
always waiting for the bridge because
she's someone that just raises the bar
so high. It's like this entire new
section for things to just absolutely go
crazier and crazier.
The pendulum is like boom boom like
every 5 seconds. Just the mania. It's
like this character is manic. I used
that word a lot to describe a fair
amount of the album.
This is the creepiest. This we were
going like hereditary with it, horror
movie style. Like, someone's on the
ceiling, kind of like exorcist style,
like head spinning. Quite awful. That's
the visual I had in mind for catch me on
your ceiling.
On the internet and at shows, I've seen
people think that the word is prize with
a Z, but it is not. It's price cuz it's
basically like
that's what you get for blocking me out.
Terrible, terrible. It's so It's so
intrusive. Okay, if I were to dissect
all the feelings in this song, there's
mania for sure. It's petty.
Jealousy.
[Music]
Anger.
Crush. The bridge did end up being the
thing that kind of
took the song on the ride. It's
interesting like what the pieces of
songs that people like pick apart and
then that is what makes it go viral.
I'm embarrassed that I included this.
This is typical of my notes at entries.
These are just some notes that
I shouldn't have sent you. So, I'll just
stand in front of them.
Well, I think that this song opened a
lot of doors in the past year
that we got to experience as a result of
the reach that this song had. I get to
do the thing that I've loved since I was
a kid, but I get to do it with people
who
I respect um and admire so much. Getting
to experience crowds feeling into the
experience of this song, you know, more
than I maybe even did when we were
writing it. It's like just like
everything else that has gone down the
past, you know, year and a half, I just
am learning from all of it in real time
and that's really everything I I think I
could possibly say about this song. Last
thing to do is
sign off. Signing for me and Audrey
because like the ghost of her is in this
room, I feel.
[Music]
That's not her signature, but just
we'll pretend.
Thank god.